Chris Pappas

Full Stack Developer seeking a role working with **great people, interesting tech** and solving **valuable problems**, and using my wide range of skills and experience as a **"force multiplier"** to help my **team succeed**.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Production Engineer Shopify, Remote

Nov 2021 - May 2023

- Observability UX team, implementing an O11y solution using Grafana and Prometheus, integrating with all production systems across Shopify
- Grafana custom plugin development using React and Typescript as well as Golang, updates and modifications to a fork of Grafana itself
- GraphQL API backend using Golang and MySQL/BigQuery
- CI using Buildkite and Docker including Unit and Acceptance Tests, Linting, and deployment to Kubernetes

Senior Software Engineer

APOLLO Insurance, Remote

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021

- Full stack Lambda Serverless development
- NodeJS, DynamoDB and React

Staff Software Engineer

Glacier FarmMedia, Winnipeg, Canada

Nov 2017 - Jul 2021

- Tech Lead and Full Stack development of the AgDealer.com online platform.
- Laravel/PHP backend using Elasticsearch and MS SQL Server, REST API, Async Queue Workers, Lambda NodeJS image processing. VueJS frontend with LoginRadius and Google Tag Manager/Analytics.
- Server administration on AWS including RDS database management, Linux system admin, Nginx and Apache configuration.
- DevOps implementation using Gitlab CI with custom runners, and a local development platform using Docker and Docker-compose.
- Team lead for developers and remote consultants to build the backend data platform to drive ingestion into the MS SQL Server database and then into Elasticsearch. Search analysis and indexing configuration and tuning. Search term and aggregation development

pappas.christopher@gmail.com (204) 612-0800

Winnipeg, Canada

linkedin.com/in/chris-pappas github.com/chrispappas chrispappas.dev

TOP SKILLS

Golang, PHP, Node, Laravel, Hugo React, Vue, Typescript, GraphQL SQL, Elasticsearch, DynamoDB Git, DevOps, Kubernetes, Linux Nginx, Apache, Varnish DNS, Cloudflare, Hosting

ABOUT ME

I am a **full-stack dev** with experience across a wide range of technologies and industries, and a passion for **learning new things** and **making new connections**. I have worked in organizations from 10 to 10,000, on teams of 3 to 13+, and one attribute I'm often credited with and **proud** of, is being a **great team player**.

I am an experienced people leader, but my real love is writing code and seeing it work. I believe in unit and automated testing, but I'm not a TDD zealot. My Git history is clean and well-commented, and I appreciate a really well-crafted Pull Request or Issue Description as much as a detailed Readme file. Updating documentation is something I have incorporated into my development cycle, and I have thanked myself many times for just writing it down.

I love solving new problems and fixing what's broken.

Senior Developer Team Lead

Bold Commerce, Winnipeg, Canada

May 2016 - Nov 2017

- Team lead for E-commerce R&D Projects using Youtube video player with Mithril and Vuejs based overlay
- Laravel/PHP REST API development using MySQL
- Kubernetes and CI DevOps for production and staging deployments

Associate Manager

IG Wealth Management, Winnipeg, Canada

Nov 2014 - May 2016

- Managed a team of front-end developers in the Marketing Department
- Content management for the main corporate website, investor relations site and large-scale employee intranet sites
- Custom application development using Angular and VueJS

Front-End Web Developer

Tipping Canoe, Winnipeg, Canada

Aug 2011 - Oct 2014

- Web developer at Tipping Canoe, specializing in front-end design and implementation across many web properties including HotUKDeals.com
- Developed and implemented a full SASS component library for the UI and UX of HotUKDeals, used by myself and the implementation team to rebuild and redesign the site

EDUCATION

University of Manitoba

B.Sc. (Comp. Sci.)

Apr 2009

Elasticsearch

Engineer I & II

2019